# WEI YANG HONG

hongwy@u.nus.edu · LinkedIn · GitHub

Avid software developer/enthusiast familiar with helping create detailed application codes and design. Extensive collaboration with developers/designers from around the world to draft and test programs for in-field rollout. Knowledge-able in version control and popular frontend frameworks necessary for software development.

Experienced in low level languages like C/C++ for performance-based application as well as scripting languages like python for quick prototyping.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN, YIPIT DATA - EDISON SOFTWARE

San Jose, CA | 2021 - Current

Working alongside QA engineers and UI/UX designers headquartered in China and California to develop a frontend iOS/Android webmail via React Native.

- Built upon and debugged native Android java/iOS Swift libraries that are open sourced for certain unique feature requests.
- Developed and debugged UI screens for multiple purposes which were requested by designers and users, and eventually deployed into production once tested by QA.

## SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN, NUS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Singapore | 2019 - 2021

Co-developed a wireless sensor prototype via a 3-tier architecture. (Dec 2019 - May 2020)

- Developed the back-end python scripts required for the sensor to automatically capture data and wireless statistics 24/7.
- Developed a user-friendly configurable web dashboard via React library and Node.js backend for the communication between the database and the dashboard

Co-developed an automated solution for IoT devices to be connected to NUS campus network. (Jun 2020 - Jan 2021)

- Developed the HTTP APIs needed for each automated actions and account authentication via Django framework
- Developed and documented the front-end dashboard alongside a UI/UX designer from a wireframe via React library and Material-UI

### **EDUCATION**

# **BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING - EXPECTED IN MAY 2022**

National University of Singapore | Singapore Computer Engineering Teaching Assistant for CS2113T Software engineering and principles. Current GPA: 4.21/5.0

# **EXCHANGE- MAY 2021**

Stanford University | San Jose Management Science & Engineering Took entrepreneurship courses under NUS Overseas College Scholarship

# **SKILLS**

- Software Development
- Git
- Javascript/React/React Native/NodeJS

- Django/Python
- HTML/CSS
- Java